lan Matsumoto

DATA ANALYST

CONTACT



Milpitas, CA 95035



808-679-7230



ianmat55@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/ianmatsumoto

PROFILE

Ian Matsumoto is a GIS Analyst, freelancer and programmer.

Travelling to the Bay Area from his hometown of Honolulu HI, Ian is pursuing his passion for creative innovation through a career in technology. He carries with him 5+ years of experience with GIS technologies, a love for computer science, and an exceptional work ethic.

EDUCATION

University of Redlands

2015 - 2019

Major:

Envoronmental Science

GIS

Minor:

Mathematics

SKILLS

Technologies:

GIS based systems

Git

Lidar and remote sensing

Languages:

Python

Java

Some JavaScript

Professional:

Project management and QA processing

New hire training

Workflow coordination

Technical writing

EXPERIENCE

Data Annotation Specialist

Tesla | 10/2020 - present

Assist in the training and development of Tesla autopilot ai through the use of GIS and data labeling

- Used the Tesla autopilot labeling interface to identify areas critical to training the neural network
- Collaborated with computer vision engineers to help improve the design of efficient labelling interfaces
- Promoted to the QA team and learned about the general workflow to QA process
- Gained basic knowledge of computer vision, lidar, and machine learning to better understand how this data can be used to label edge cases encountered by autopilot

Freelance Web Developer

2/2021 - present

Self-taught programmer specializing in website development using Wordpress and Shopify.

- Create websites for clients using html, css and javascript
- Work with hosting platforms, content management systems and APIs
- Specialize in commerce development as well as personal/professional website development

GIS Analyst

Apple via Apex Systems | 07/2019 - 09/2020

Used GIS software to mark construction projects that would affect routing or address changes in Apple Maps

- Conduct web research on construction projects in Riverside County and Orange County
- Update Apple maps and record all significant projects in respective counties using GIS software, Excel and Quip
- Communicate and collaborate with city/county officials and private companies regarding new projects